PATRICK REAGAN

EXPERIENCED SOFTWARE ENGINEER AND LEADER

CONTACT

└ <u>703-303-7977</u>

□ patrick@the-reagans.com

in linkedin.com/in/reagent

ு github.com/reagent

9 Boulder, CO

EDUCATION

Bachelor's Degree, Computer Science

James Madison University Harrisonburg, VA

SKILLS

Programming Languages

TypeScript / Ruby / Rust / PHP / Golang / Python

Frameworks

Rails / Sinatra / Django / Laravel / Express / Nest.js

Databases

PostgreSQL / SQLite / Redis

SOFTWARE PROJECTS

PostgreSQL Migrator (Rust)

A basic migrator library that will apply SQL files to a PostgreSQL database

Fleakr (Ruby)

A full-featured API client for Flickr photostreams

Blog Service (TypeScript)

An Express application for managing posts to a blog

dnsimple (Python)

Re-imagining improved ergonomics for interacting with the DNSimple API

minecraft-server (Ansible / Python)

Simplifying setup and teardown of family Minecraft servers

SUMMARY

I am an experienced, pragmatic software developer with a love for code quality, collaboration, and continuous improvement. I excel at breaking down complex engineering problems and building applications that deliver value across a diverse set of business domains.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Staff Software Engineer

Ideon | January 2023 - October 2023

At Ideon, I expanded our enrollments platform to connect benefit administration providers with a diverse set of insurance carriers.

- Led integration and onboarding of a new carriers to expand insurance benefit offerings and realize additional Q4 revenue
- Improved platform reliability by focusing on a behavioral testing approach that exposed bugs and allowed for better regression prevention
- Organized and led a bi-weekly cross-functional engineering meeting to showcase team achievements and share technology trends
- Mentored other engineers through focused pair-programming sessions and code reviews

Principal Engineer

KindHealth | February 2021 - December 2022

At KindHealth, I built technology solutions to help scale their growing brokerage business.

- Reworked critical pieces of their PostgreSQL database schema which improved data integrity and allowed us to capture more commission revenue
- Simplified operational complexity by migrating from a SQS / serverless setup to a proven Redis-backed queuing solution that provided better resilience at their smaller scale
- Improved the stability of their core platform through the addition of an integration test layer which allowed the team to more quickly develop features and squash bugs
- Built a shared data access library that provided a migration pathway away from an untested legacy Express / JavaScript backend towards a modern Nest.js / TypeScript backend
- Fostered an engineering culture of constant improvement through thoughtful code reviews, tech-focused presentations, and one-on-one remote pairing sessions with other engineers

Staff Engineer: Platform

Gloo | November 2019 - January 2021

As Staff Engineer, I architected and built several HTTP-based microservices in support of various in-market applications.

- Improved the quality and delivery of a variety of TypeScript microservices through better API design, thorough testing, and meaningful code reviews
- Helped scale an existing Rails API by directing database reads to be performed against our read-only Aurora replica to handle unique traffic spikes
- Led bi-weekly meetings that provided a venue for engineers to share best practices for application development, demonstrate platform observability features, and keep the team up-to-date on relevant technologies
- Coordinated and directed contractor teams in assisting with feature planning and bug fixes for critical in-market products and supporting microservices

PATRICK REAGAN

EXPERIENCED SOFTWARE ENGINEER AND LEADER

PUBLICATIONS

Advanced Rails Recipes (2009)

Pragmatic Bookshelf (Contributing Author)

A Practical Guide to WinCVS and SSH (2002)

CvsGui Project

Using Oracle With PHP (2001)

WebMonkey (Wired Digital)

PRESENTATIONS

<u>Coding with Confidence: Adding TDD to Your Toolset</u>

CMAP Fall Code Camp | 2009

Effective Testing for Rails Projects

Ruby Hack Day | 2009

Make Everyone a Tester: Natural Language Acceptance Testing

Developer Day DC & CVREG | 2009

<u>Changing Your Mindset: Getting Started</u> <u>with Test-Driven Development</u>

Lone Star Ruby Conference | 2007

Mockfight! Flexmock v. Mocha

NovaRUG | 2007

WORK EXPERIENCE (CONT.)

Development Director

Viget | June 2005 - November 2019

In addition to my work developing applications for a variety of clients, I also:

- Helped grow the company's presence in Boulder from a single person co-working outpost into a full-fledged office
- Created and refined our engineering hiring process in order to provide consistency in evaluation and ensure that only the top candidates were considered for in-person evaluations
- Established, planned, and led the engineering team's bi-annual offsite meetings as a means to connect personally and improve professionally
- Improved software delivery by introducing agile methods that included iteration planning, acceptance test-driven development, and iteration retrospectives

Applications Technologist

Viget | November 2000 - June 2005

- Administered internal and client servers running a variety of operating systems, web servers, and databases
- Developed custom database-backed web applications for clients using a variety of languages, databases, and deployment configurations
- Provided technical leadership in the areas of payment systems integration and application performance
- Advocated and implemented development standards that included the use of version control, API documentation, and automated unit and integration testing
- Developed a reusable MVC framework written in PHP that streamlined the application development process

Senior Web Developer

Millennium Health Communications | April 2000 - October 2000

- Developed sweeping enhancements to the existing medical auction site using ASP with a SQL Server back-end this included creating an online RFP service from the ground up
- Configured and deployed a Linux server for use as an internal web, database, DNS, and file server
- Developed a custom syndication engine in VBScript/ASP that used XML to provide health news to content subscribers
- Developed an internal PHP application to serve as a lightweight CMS for the organization

Software Engineer

Dyncorp Information Systems | June 1999 - April 2000

- Helped develop the interface for a web-based stock trading system that hooked into proprietary server-side software components
- Developed enhancements to the OpenView network monitoring system deployed to the NYSE